Hi, I'm jeff irwin and happy to be doing this talk on channel nine for as
...storage welcome to the talk we're going to be
talking about the storage perform performance scaleability and security.
So, in this talk we're going to be covering just a brief overview storage those of you looking for
introduction to storage aimee strongly encourage you to check out jason hogs talk that
will be actually at build checked I'll give you...full overview of
our service what it can do different data types those of you who are more familiar with the
stored service already using it familiar with it definitely check out this talk
follow along this hopefully we'll be productive for you we'll also talk about storage
internals see understand design principles
and architecture choices that you can make and then we'll go into just some
quick five-minute fixes that you can make to your code that should markedly
improved performance and including one set well where we'll take a code sample
improve its performance by about ninety nine percent so definitely stick around for
that and finally will also be talking about...security considerations we've had a lot of
developers asking us lately about security considerations for as your storage so we
...make sure we take a few minutes ago...that?
Says start off with just a few minutes as a reminder about as
...storage.
We have it's durable cloud storage really and it comes in a few different
flavors but that's really our goal is storing all your data
with high durability in the cloud accessible from anywhere we
do three strongly consistent copies in one region plus optional
...with option only with geo redundant storage you can have three more
copies geo replicated to another region for even more durable storage.
Really high scale at the moment we're currently serving millions of transactions
every second and, we already have trillions of...stored so,
were...very high scale many of the largest
microsoft services are using as...storage already so,
that should give you some idea of just how scale we can operate at and,
how you can use a...your applications...finally flexible we?
We use rest apis for all interaction with
the storage platform means you can use it from any platform you can use it from you know,
any platform you want that's part of your application we have fully supported libraries
in dot net windows phone windows runtime android java cplus-plus
node dot js coming more all the time
...making sure that the cplus-plus.
And, java libraries work on both windows and linux so,
we really want to embrace whatever platform works for your application so,
that you don't have to do anything unnaturally use storage and,
if we don't have a particular language you need as we said they're just rest apis you can always
write directly against those.
Storage types as you storage is really flexible platform first type weeks
support is called blobs there's really two types of these this block blogs and page
blobs the block blobs...for just ordinary content...you know,
any photos or documents logs files anything that
you would normally read and write all at one-time and ranges
is well-suited for block clubs
...page blobs most common scenario for page blobs is going-to be
disk so anybody who's using as your disks that's all page blob page
blob data underneath you can also use it in a few other scenarios for random read
right particularly if you're doing random
...you may want to aexplore page blobs?
Next up we have files this is support the sm be protocol
from the cloud so you can access, access it just like a file share the
one interesting characteristic as opposed to...as you can access it from many of lms
...time whereas a disk can only be mounted by a single vm so-if you have data that you need to
share among multiple of gm's
and, measure compute you can you can use the measure file service?
And, we have tables this is a...sequel store most
frequently used as a key value look up that...for structured data it's,
you know, grow like data but schema less you don't have to have the same schema
forever row that will be digging into quite a bit.
And, then finally we have...which is for durable messaging this is for handing
off messages between components of your application and making sure that
app the those messages are never lost they can be resumed and,
that message always gets fully processed.
Next we're going to talk about storage internals so why are we starting with internals
first.
We really find that developers who understand the internals can make much better design
choices once you understand how the platform works underneath we find that
it's much easier to figure out how should I design my application on top of
it so we're going to spend a lot of time on that the one nice thing about
this is because all of those different data types are hosted on the same
platform any of these principles will work for any of those data types
so understanding the internals will help you make design choices for a blobs tables
...any of the different data types ...are all hosted on the
same common platform.
So, the measure storage architecture really sthree tiers so, the first...the as
...storage architecture is the from and here is a stateless.
Stateless layer it's really meant for request handling
...handles all the request validation it'll do meter
ing throttle laying off all those things are handle that the front-end layer but,
it's fully stateless so any request to send
to storage service could go into any one of the front-ends beneath that we have what
with what's called the partition layer this is what really serves the
requests this is what does all the all the heavy lifting a processing
request determining what data it's four and then
fetching that data from the data layer this is the existence of this layers what
enable strong consistency batch transactions will be spending a lot of time on this today?
And, then finally we have the stream layer the stream
layer stores multiple replicas of your data again keeps durable and,
really doesn't know anything about that data logically all it does a store the data and,
make sure that it's kept...
So, as...partitions just
...start there...really the most important concept in designing your data.
A single partition is served by a single partition server so,
...it ends up being the scaleability limit and,
then a single partition server conserve multiple partitions the scale of a partition
can't exceed what a single partition server can handle so,
it's really important when designing your data that you allow your data spread across partitions.
The to kind of design considerations that are kept intention here
is that data in a single partition can be updated atomically that is it
sports batch transactions and,
other atomic operations data in separate partitions can be load
balanced across different partition servers so,
that that's you want to allow for that as much as possible there is no limit on the
number of partitions you can half so, as you start specifying partition case there's
no need to try and keep the number of partitions low you can use as many as you want?
For references the partitions are specified differently for each of
the data types for a blobs the full blob path including the blog
name is the partition key essentially each blob is its own partition
for tables the table entities each have a partition key that
you specify you may have multiple entities within a single partition key but,
all of those will always be served by the same partition server.
Then...the...name is the partition key so,
all messages in a single q will be...by the
same partition server and then for files a single file share is a partition key.
So, let's do some examples just walking through r three
...architecture and see how these requests get process.
These examples are all going to be based on the table service just in terms of what
they logically look at but you could imagine this working welfare blobs or
...or files as well so in this first example we just
have a single of object a single request for a single object and,
it's been fully specify the request is specified you know, partition aef and
...want to this happens to come into front-end number two it could have done any of
the front-ends partition server three is hosting partitions fthree
j right now so the request is going to get routed partition threebased on
it being for partition f then partition server three
find out the data is actually hosted on stream server too so it's going to rout the data
stream server to these are very fast and efficient requests.
Let's look at a second...request this one's also for partition
f but for different piece of data so you can see the request flow goes through a different
effie but again the same partition server and this is really important this is
going to the same partition server as the previous request because again it's for the same partition,
partition asf and then finally get just goes to another
stream server the data can be spread all across the stream layer.
then this is for another request a again simple request single object
...partition just goes to a different partition server you can see this one's for partition
t which...to partition server for the data happens to be on the
same stream layer server that we used in the first request but, that's mere coincidence.
And, then finally this is just an example of what we call batch request this is a
request that ask for two pieces of data it's in partition w we get down
the partition server five that serving that partition but because it needs to pieces of data
...up having to go to stream servers is a little less efficient because we need multiple
objects from multiple servers so, overall the key take away here
is address storage is going to be most efficient for single...single object
operations single partition operations are going to be much more efficient
than multi partition operations will look at a multi partition operation in a minute to show why.
Let's talk about designing your data so just to remind everybody about table server structure this is
just a sample table here reviews the user ideas the partition
key just as a side user ideas a great partition key there's no need to use
the first to characters or anything like that you can just use the user id maybe a
guid or hash of the user idea if you want to make
it random that works as a great partition key even if you have millions of them next we have
...keys that's going to be you know, specifically identifying
an identity within a partition and then finally with each entity we have a set
of properties again table storage is scheme unless you can have any
...properties associated with each entity they don't have to follow all the sameschema.
So, just to walk through the table structure.
...this is the kind of key points here you've got entities with the same partition
key are always...by the same server so all these with user id one are going to be
served by the same partition server user id to may be
served by the same partition server it could be served by another one.
Then we talked about
...have properties but they can be completely different across different and, this.
So, let's talk about three different query scenarios.
We look at a us cities table for an example here so this is
a table of just some cities in the...of washington so,
are you will be state as the partition key and then city as the...key and,
then just as an example property
with put the population of each city into the in the property values?
So, as we talked about before this is very similar to what we looked at earlier we're looking at the us
cities table partition key as washington parochial
seattle we're going to end up over on partition server five because washington start with
the w...then going back to stream server to for that object.
This is really efficient
that's one object from one partition is really what storage is designed to do
it's very fast very efficient as you work do this is the second scenario
second scenario here you have partitions...partition scanned you see that we've
specified a particular a specific partition key washington still so,
we're only involving one partition but now we've just put a
filter on population just said all cities with more than ten thousand people.
This is still going to be a little less efficient as you see we've involved now
to data servers we're...have to scan a lot more entities in order to be able to
...respond with the data and finally we have table scans these are by far the least
efficient operations in storage because these spanned partitions
this is similar if you were using the blob service to doing a list blobs operation or
...doing list...me spanning partitions to do those operations and
what you see is this kind of fan out as...using multiple partition
servers multiple stream servers in order to get all the us cities with more than ten
thousand people these are really efficient we want to avoid...time we can...applications?
What's the cost of scans...first one for
...your application...to be slower what you see is that
...inefficient they're going to take much longer than point queries?
One of the reasons for that is when you look at scaleability and limits.
Table stored can handle twenty thousand entities per second that's based on the number of entities scanned
and written request that scans a thousand entities to return one counts
...or counts as a thousand not one so,
you can see how you can quickly pile up the number of entity scan and get to that scaleability
target actually very quickly what happens when you exceed that scaleability target you'll find
...stored account starts to get throttled another piece here is when you see this thousand
and one ratio all that time scanning
is time not spent returning data which means
is just going to have a negative impact on the performance...application?
So, how do we avoid them so, we're going to look at an example right now how to turn...table scan into a
partition scanned this make a pretty big improvement and application?
So, just turntable scans in the partition scans or partition scans into
the point queries we use d normalization this is a
word that if you're coming from a sequel background probably is not something you been
...to do over the years but,
in table...actually a really beneficial approach
...normal is neat d normalize data allows you to query efficiently get
exactly the data that you need and,
unlike relational databases table storage is very cheap and,
you see the price there it ends up being really cheap to store lots of
data so duplicating data doesn't have a cost that maybe it in on...and other databases?
So, again, back to our us cities sample the partition key
here was state name and queries across states require table scams so when I
wanted to do a query for all the cities that have more than
a hundred-thousand people are more than ten thousand people I had to include multiple partition
servers to complete that operation that's going to be just faria...efficient
and also what you see here is we will scanned many entities but only returned a few so,
just the density of results that was return was very low.
So, now if we try and improve this table we keep all the entities that we
had before because we may want to perform queries where we say get me the population
of seattle wa and not-so-nice fast point query so we kept that
but now we've added additional pop partition...which are population ranges
...we have a partition that covers cities that are ten thousand two hundred-thousand
and cities that are hundred-thousand to a million and then we've put the role key is the
state...and city name so now when we want to do a
scanned for all the cities that are within a particular partition or within
a particular population range now we can get that all from one partition?
And, then this is what you end up for exactly the same query we
were doing earlier you now see that we only have to
insult involve one partition server instead of three like
we did before this is still a partition scanned so it's still going to have to hit multiple data
...multiple stream servers but we've made it much more efficient than it was before.
So, you see is we've avoided scans by
doing the normalization you can use exactly the same principle if you have a lot of
partitions scans you-can refactoring...data to enable point queries and,
the cost effectiveness of table storage is really what allows us to work again,
you can apply this to blobs,
for example, if you were doing list operations because you're constantly looking for a blob
based on one particular attribute you may consider
duplicating that blob with that attribute in the name so you can find it much more quickly.
Now going to talk a little bit about query first design you saw an example of this in the previous
...in the us cities that we walk through but really this is the core
of how we design our data...as your storage that means is start
...determining what queries you will perform again if you're coming from
a relational database background you may be more familiar with starting with what
you're storing starting with the objects and designing your
data around that in as your storage you really want to start more
from the queries of saying what will I want to know or what I want to do and,
then...the data for that...previous example we knew they were to potentially common
query so we d normalize the data to make both of them more efficient?
So, for example, we're going to look at a sample here maybe from
and e-commerce application the example here is if
we have customer orders with retention policy so we think about customer
orders one of the things that's going to happen a lot is somebody's going to want to be able to look up
by a specific customer by a particular order id getting the
data about those about those customer transactions customer orders you may also want to
...the whole list of orders that were perform by
a particular customer but that's much more rare that a customers
...want their whole history so we don't need to optimize for that
as heavily and then finally there's an additional requirement
here which is for privacy and security reasons we said every transaction
...order from the customer needs to be deleted the record of it needs
to be deleted after six months we can't hold onto it longer than that
so we need to make sure that rand-r tables actually enabled that scenario fairly well.
So, first try here is again,
what you might do coming from a relational database you have a partition key
hear from user id that's good then we ad in a row key that's the order idea within
that user id and, then some metadata about that
order stables great for finding all the orders for a particular user but,
we don't do that very often it's also good for finding a specific order
by a specific user id but,
one thing that this table won't be good for is finding all the orders to delete
so if you imagine that every day I want to find everything that's more than six-months-old
the only way to do that is to scan the entire
table and find anything that has a partition key...older than six months?
This set of tables improves on that so what we've done here is now
we've said because I have this retention policy that's really important to me I'm going
to be doing it all the time I'm going to do is I'm actually in a split out my orders by
...you could use a different time range you could use a day or week depending on
your application needs but we've split out the tables so,
that each of them captures orders from a particular time range that way as soon as that table
as more than six-months-old you can simply delete the entire table which is only
one operation finding all the orders for a particular user you're
...to have to query multiple tables now maybe six if you're using one per month but,
we already said that operation is quite rare compared to
other retention policy and even that would just basic
partitions scans no table scans involved
in this so this is going to be much more efficient based on the queries that we have
...you could imagine a different application with different queries and it would have different means and,
we might design the tables different differently for that but by starting with what we
need to know and designing the data for that we've ended up with some tables that are really going to make our
application performance and not run into the scaleability targets like we would have with the first traffic.
Next one will look at is hot partitions this can happen in blob storage
...can happening q storage can happen and table storage can happen in
any of these and really gets to how do you again how do you efficiently
the structure data so what is a pop-pop partition
...one partition in your in your storage account that's
taking much more of the load than any other partition so you have a single blob that's
really commonly access or a single partition key that's really commonly
...what ends up happening is we've talked about before is it presents
a scale limit because we can't split across multiple partition servers so it can't be
load balanced which means you'll hit your throughout you'll hit the throttle in limits
much earlier than you'd like to so we want to avoid those wherever possible so
this is just kind of an illustration very quickly in terms of how this ends up working we
say partition start off well...we've got five hundred transactions per second
happening across all the partition servers only say well what if
partitioned server d and e start getting more traffic now there's an imbalance
measure storage is a self load balancing prop platform
so it'll go ahead and actually automatically split out partition
servers two and three it'll maybe move partition...to a different partition server
to the cool things down and get them back out more balanced but what you see here
is that partition dee can't be load balanced anymore
it's now stuck there's no ability to split things out so it's doing a thousand
gps on that server and,
you know, it may be able to increase a little bit more but at some point it's going to run into
the limit of what that server can do at that point you'll
get throttle laying and other...
So, an example of how partitions we see is logging so,
...look at that.
When...logging from multiple servers something people would do all the time
as that they would use partition...partition key that's just
the days date it feels natural it was my first try when I did logging
was to just put in today's date as the partition key the time stamp ends up being the
...key and then some properties the problem with this is the vast majority of
inserts in fact all of your inserts will always be hitting one partition my experience
in a lot of logging situations insert is by far the most common action
read is far less-common which means the vast majority of operations
against this table are going to be against a single partition key which means
that will work right up until the moment that you have too many
servers to many events and all the sudden you'll be hearing that single partition server limit?
So, what we've done here is we've improve this by giving each server its...partitions so maybe
I have eighteen servers are more and, I'll have each server writing to
its own partition this one represent a little bit of a drawback in the in order to find
and event I may have to do multiple partition scans but again we said reading
is much more rare than inserting data and this allows each of the
servers to be writing to its own partition to avoid hitting any sort of partition
key scaleability limit?
The last thing that you might consider
doing with logging is actually to not use tables at all to use blobs so
if you use blobs what you find is log data can frequently be written,
written and batches you can batch it up for a few minutes and then write it out to blobs and,
then have each of your servers doing this and then also logs are frequently
read in ranges you may want to retrieve all the logs for a particular our for particular
five minutes so we've done here is done exactly the same thing but we're using a
blob container and,
time range for each of the each of the ranges of time for container?
So, in summary we're looking at designing
...data across all the different service servers.
You want to choose a great partition key I can be the blog path the table keys to
name it really matters for all the data types because partitions end up being the limiting
...scalability factor as long as you spread your data across partitions
you're going to get great scalability out of measure storage as I said before
...table or blob storage any of these can have
millions of partition case so don't be afraid to use user id is
...is anything like that as your partition key allows
for really even load balancing d normalization is a great way to again,
improve your query efficiency by
the duplicating the data making it easier to find the right table entity or
...finally use the right abstraction sometimes blobs are great.
The solution even though it's structured data sometimes you may want to use tables
or files use the right abstraction for your data
in general blobs are going to be great for data that's written and batches or...and ranges and,
then tables are going to be great for data that's a key value lookup.
now we talked about kind of...internals and specific queries and query patterns that
you can do now we're going to talk a little bit more about designing your application and some patterns that we
see that can really help your application do well either by using storage
...using storage more efficiently the first one will talk about this is one that
...a lot of applications actually doing which is just using cues
todistribute work to a back-end role so, in this example we've used
a q front-end takes in a request for maybe some long-running process
that front-end instead of doing that longing process
long-running process itself and blocking blocking out cpu resources on that
...it's going to put that messaging...let the
back-end workers handle it and, puts maybe store the results back
...as your storage this allows for asynchronous processing more
responsive front-ends and then also very importantly
independent scaling you can have to front-ends while you have a thousand back ends
or any ratio you need to make sure that you're getting the performance that you
Another thing that
we've seen a lot of people doing recently is simple change notifications so,
some people sometimes you'll say I need to know when a blob
changed or...the changed so you'll start listing the blobs
repeatedly or scanning a table repeatedly because we've already talked about those
lists and scans those are table scans and they're not going to be very efficient so,
instead of doing that you can see a process here for implementing a very
simple change notification pattern so basically you have the client making
the change prior to making that change put...message and, one of your
cues that describes that chained what object what changed was deleted was
specifies that then the client making the change makes the change so,
it does the...message...so that we make sure that the client didn't crash
right after making the change we want-to make sure that the change was captured and
then observer watches for the...the...regularly instead of listing blogger
tables pulling...is very efficient when it gets a message checks to see if the expected
change happened if it did it process...if not it can let the...message go back to the
...those of you familiar with queues that's a kind of core concept of using as your
...and, then, you know,
you can let it go back to q then try again later on the same message
q messages have a dq count so you can see when the messages
...the queued maybe three times once that's happened maybe you can
assume that the client that was trying to make the change actually failed after it updated the
...message you can just throw-away the key message and assume
that the chained was on successful one important thing?
Here as I said you really need to make sure that the
...message was created before the changes made otherwise you could lose the
lose the fact that the changes made and, not perform whatever processing...to.
Using shared access signatures which we're going to talk about more in a minute and
cross origin resource sharing you can now actually make direct data access calls
from your client devices so,...used to be that you would have to proxy all as
your storage datathrough your front-end front-end web roles that would
...timor front-end web roles you need to be thinking about
scalability just as much as the storage platform needs to and,
now we have shared access signatures which allow for a delegated access
across origin resource sharing headers which help with browsers security
features to allow the device to just get minimal amounts of data
from the front-end and then turn around and send request for additional data
to add your storage directly not requiring your front-end to scale nearly as much?
Also let's talk about disks so, with disks your...targets
...very important here you have five hundred I...per disk twenty thousand I apps per
...which means you can't have more than forty discs per
count so, if you're going to have more than forty disks definitely spread those across storage
accounts you can have up to a hundred storage accounts per subscription avoiding the per
...scaleability target best practice for that is striving this you can use storage spaces
to ensure that even load distribution and, you can...up to a
...easily even using our show you can go even more than that
so definitely striped ist if you're going to be going anywhere beyond that five hundred I
opts to make sure that you get good performance.
We also have a premium disks now generally available ready for your ready for
your use gets you hire I...per disk and, then additionally.
In addition to...the higher apps produce also
hire throughput so, you see the smallest disco p term has five hundred I
...disco hundred megabytes per second all the way up to a p thirty has a terabyte of data
five thousand miles and two hundred megabytes per second so much higher
limits than were available on standard storage this is all as us feedback so,
you're also going to get much lower latency much more consistent latency then you maybe got
with standard disk so same best practices
...all built on similar a similar platforms...best practices apply stripe for more
apps one note here is to make sure using the appropriate vm size,
for example, a ds one can only do thirty two hundred I apps so,
you probably wouldn't want to pair that with a p thirty...that can do
five thousand you should use at least a ds to make sure that you can get all the app to looking for.
So, what we're going to look at right now is about ten five-minute fixes each of
these are really simple for you to go and add your code today and,
each of them should make a really big difference in your in your applications performance
starting off with a couple that are that are useful for all the different data types the
first one's going to be using read from secondary this is usually not thought of as a performance
fix this is usually thought of as availability or durability change?
But, from your users' perspective if...requesting data from your service and
you're trying that request on the primary and the primary for some
reason is temporarily unavailable you can immediately
fail back to the secondary to get that data
...immediately for the user improving their perceive latency actually
quite a bit couple notes on this one it only takes justand,
even half of...line of code adding in this location mode for re tries and,
that supported across again all the data types blobs tables
...files.
But, one note here just remember the secondary copy is eventually consistent so
if it's a very recent write it may not be reflected yet.
One other one we see I've made this mistake and, we've seen
...a number of times make sure that this line creative not exists is not in
your mainline code
repeatedly this line of code always makes at least one server call and,
usually isn't...necessary once you've created your applications
tables so typically a want to pull those out create all your
tables up-front and then let your mainline code
just for focus on the operation it's performing not making sure that the table exists?
With queues you can use update
message update message allows you to do a couple of different things.
What this is once I've retrieved a message?
In...you have to...delete you retrieve and then you delete a message so once you
retrieved the message you-can call back an update that message
you-can update both the least time that you have the invisibility time to
give yourself more time to process the message and you can update the contents of that message
so in this case what we've done is we've said both I want to update the invisibility
timeout to give myself more time hanover
updated the comment the content to say I'm done with some step one
what this allows is if my worker were to fail?
If my...word fail.
Than I can resume.
On the next worker from step one I don't have to start over all the way from
the beginning again so this is a really good way to make sure that your application can be
much more responsive doesn't have to read perform a lot of work that it was doing earlier or
the had already been done and also allows you to use much shorter
invisibility time-outs you don't have to make sure that it's the longest possible amount of time
thatprocess could take because you can kind of...that lease regularly
and allow another worker to get started more quickly and the event the era worker fails.
For copying blobs we support asynchronous server-side copy blob
this really helps your application scale if you're trying to copy a lot of data you can
actually just call copy blob on our service and then the storage service
will actually copy that data for you don't have
to be able to handle that from within your within your clients virtual machines
...really improve your scale save you a lot of bandwidth there's also a
...side of this one which is
there is no guarantee provided on the amount of copy time usually it's fast but,
it is a queuing mechanism so,
in some cases it may take some time so if you do have
...scenario where you need
to guaranteed amount of time to copy it's definitely
suggested that you would use of gm somewhere in that in the as
your region and perform the copy directly to make sure that you
get a very consistent time to completion.
Parallel block upload this is just a really simple fix that you can do when
you're uploading files we don't do it by default in the client
library because we don't know what device will be running on what else you have going on that device so
we try and be responsible about the amount of resources
will consume but if you set up just a couple lines here around the thread count the
default connection limit this allows one blob the upload much more quickly by
using multiple connections if your uploading many blobs upload blobs
in parallel this goes back to the partition limits we were talking about earlier in terms of if
...uploading many blobs that's sending different request to different partitions and,
allowing that scale-up scale out
affect as opposed to putting all of the traffic against a single partition.
So, better way to do this is to do to specific what we call point queries
to specific queries for a specific
...this one feels a little bit less
efficient because now I'm making to server calls but each of them now is a single
point query instead of a partition scanned so it's much more efficient just trying it out on my
deb box no specific optimized environment anything like that I didn't even
make them in parallel just trying this versus the previous slide consistently
perform five...faster five times better than the previous solution.
So, let's talk about inserting...so if I had a thousand entities to answer and,
you can see my simple entities here or it's just going to be...partition
key of standard and then just the number zero through
nine-ninety nine in the ...key this might be one way to insert a
thousand and it is just loop through loop through the numbers insert each one of them one-at-a-time.
So, on my machine this
...one hundred nine seconds to complete not bad but I wanted to do better.
So, first thing I do is I turn angle off so, nagel goals algorithm
is an algorithm that can help in certain networks circumstances does not
help with table storage...storage or any very small operations against the
storage service so we generally recommend turning it off so,
you can see using...service point manager...to turn it off for the table service and
point you could also turn it off globally either
way but this kind of narrows it down to just the table and point in case you need on
for something else and then we try exactly the same code as we had before now you can
see the graphs in terms of the time to complete a number of and,
the inserts we've now decreased one hundred nine seconds down the forty-two?
Now let's try making these in parallel so,
we've now continue to set nagel off but, now we're going to do parallel
and the inserts allowing for actually up to ten
...to be...the time just using a dot
net parallel for each nothing nothing fancy here so now
we've dropped from forty two seconds down to four seconds by putting this in parallel?
Table support batch transactions
that the one part of this that isn't necessarily applicable to blobs are...but,
for tables we can get even better and,
that we can say do batch operation so these couple lines of code
combine with the four loop now has
multiple batch transactions going on each of them contains a hundred insert
operations that can be executed in a single batch so this now gets down
to one-point-seven seconds by making only ten calls instead of a thousand
calls?
Then finally of course we can
make those batch transactions in parallel so, again,
...depart parallel for each we've created the batches only ten requests
and finally we've gotten down to about half a second from the original hundred
nine seconds so about ninety nine-point-five percent faster
again just a few lines of code here so these are definitely things that you should
go back to your applications and make sure that you're doing nagel parallelism
and using batch requests.
...security what we're going to cover in this in this section as
...off methods we support shared
key shared access signatures and public and then encryption methods as well?
So, in off methods.
We support to the have been around the for very long
time shared key which is each account has
to shared keys that give you access to everything in the account...admin keys you can do
deletes you can you can do rights you can do are create.
Read anything on any object and the account can be done with the shared t shared key is used to
sign requests you can read in our documentation how all of that work how
that works then we support public access so you can configure blog container to
be public read access and then this is great for web content all
reads will succeed rights delete all of that is still all shared key only.
So, for shared access signatures to talk a little bit about how they work today the one thing
that's worth remembering about shared access signatures is
...computed not stored so shared access signatures the account owner
creates a string that represents the request permissions saying how long
they're good for what permissions the user can get what objects that they can reference
...they sign that string with the air with their shared key send the signature and that
string to the user the user includes those with the request as part
of the url and, then the user tries to make the request when the server
receives that request it takes that permission string and tries to sign up with
the shared key again if that matches the signature that was provided the request
as loud if not the request we this lab.
Some notes on this as I said they're not stored
there computed this means you can have as many as you want there's no limit to the number
of sas tokens you can use the number of permissions that you can specify.
You can store what's called a stored access policy on a blog container
...can be reference by the assess tokens this makes...tokens revoke
...means that you can remove that stored access policy and all of the sas tokens that
referenced we'll fail.
If some sas improvements coming this summer so,...this is just to let, you
know, they're on their waysome improvements to it that
actually are in response to a lot of user feedback so, a lot of the
developers out there and giving us great feedback on shared access signatures so these are
a few improvements we have this summer to help address that the first of these is account
...so this is men long requested its the ability to create one
sas token that applies to an entire account the
most important capability this gives you can rate one read-only sas token for
entire account and really give somebody read-only access to your
...entire storage...you don't have to give out the shared keys
anymore in fact by the by giving read and write permissions or read write
and delete even your application in the cloud doesn't need to use the
shared key anymore with this you really can you share access
signatures for everything and we definitely recommend using them wherever possible.
The second one of the one of the pitfalls of
shared access signature is if it were to be used over http.
Because anybody who captures that signature can then use it from wherever they
are say we want to make sure that the user using the shared access signature uses
it over https so now we actually support putting additional option on the
sas string saying this
sas can only be used over https.
And, that will make sure that token will fail at any applications that we're trying to use it that
...can be fixed the last one again goes it kind of a similar
thread of what if somebody gets the sas token and wasn't supposed to this
is ip act called sas or ip limited sows this allows you to put
ip address and ip address range on the permission
string which makes the shared access signature only
usable from that particular ip address so even if somebody else were to get
that shared access signature they wouldn't be able to use it unless they were at that ip.
Also actually during build we're going-to be releasing
are client-side encryption preview so, a lot of people
of asking been asking how do I encrypt my data so this is our first step
at making it much easier to encrypt data stored in as your storage so what
we've really been aiming for is getting best practices written into our client libraries
make it really easy to kind of transparently encrypt your data
as your uploading at...you're reading it also get really good integration with
as your key vault to make sure that key managements as easy as possible and,
then also just for a client-side encryption one of the really important things about it
...it allows you to maintain control of your keys so you could use
key vault or you could use your own key management service so it's
really important to give you the option of where you want to the story
...how you want to manage them and we've tried to make sure that you have
those options so one of the advantages to that is
stored service actually never sees the keys that you use again if you choose to use your own
keys maybe on cram if you're doing a hybrid cloud scenario you can
encrypted data on your own premises upload it to the stored service the
...service never actually see the keys that were used and,
then additionally, you know, you get flexibility
...in algorithm so we've tried to use industry-standard best practices but,
if you have other needs for compliance or security then you can use
your own algorithm or different algorithm for the encryption so when
...coming as we said it's actually available now it's actually ready for
you to use or the next month or two we really want your feedback
what supported now we have full blob upload ranger
full bob download tables you can do property level encryption so you can
actually specify which properties on each entity that you want to use and,
then...each messages encrypted we're using what we
call a envelope encryption this is again
an industry best practice for performance we generate
a symmetric key encrypted data with that symmetric key and, also
and unique initialization vector for each object and then encrypted data
what that key then we'll encrypt your key with the asymmetric key
the you provided the...method that was specified of
by the developer the nice thing about this is the as
...storage client library never actually has access to your key we just
call out to a method that does the wrapping of the a of the symmetric
...then we store the encrypted symmetric key as metadata on the encrypted
object you don't have to have any additional data store for this.
So, just let's go and look at a code sample for how this
will work so the first thing you're going to do is you're going to create a crypto service provider
abs key wrapper this is just what's use to or
...the symmetric case you pass in
the key again this is all your code this doesn't use the storage client library yet.
The next pieces as part ofthe blob options we're going to need
ablob encryption policy this says we're going to encrypt the full
blob using that wrapper that you already specified.
And, then set out on the commonly used blog
request options this was where we set parallelism and things like that earlier so,
we just set the encryption policy now and then finally we just upload blob and,
this all happens transparently this upload from stream because it has that
options provided will result in encrypted
...being uploaded all the metadata,
metadata being stored correctly download this blob.
Knew exactly the same thing on the other and we use the same options
...that we did before but again all we have to do is download
stream using that options object and all...
crips and happens transparently so we hope this makes it much easier for you
to encrypted data we don't have to have many developers writing their own encryption
methods to secure their data also we plan on extending this to
our other languages for example,
java to make sure that users who are reading and
writing using multiple client libraries will actually be able to
read the data written with the other client library and not have to implement
the different encryption methods on their own how to get started with
it check out the as your storage blog we've gotten
into an introduction code samples instructions for how to get started
...important give us feedback we're in a preview that preview won't last forever so it's
this limited preview but it's wide open for you to give us feedback we really want to
make this as great as we can for all your scenarios so, that so,
you can really secure your data seriously so we have somerelated content as well for you to
go ahead and take a look at after the after this talk first is the
adders stored performance and scalability checklist this is on as your dot com
and goes through all the best practices we just talked about and more again,
very quick fixes things that you can make changes to your application today
make it perform much faster we also now have the table design guide that just came
out recently and has the table design patterns that we just talked about in terms of
...partitions
...query first design and many more that are that are great for you to include
in your applications and finally the as your swords blog definitely you know,
put that in your favorites make sure that
you're checking that regularly for any announcements tips and
tricks things like that you can be aware of great thanks very much for watching I do want to
...couple other resources definitely take a
look at the asher the rest of the as your talks on channel nine so,
you can get more of a picture of the as your platform also make sure if
you're at build the to ...jason hog stock he's going to be talking
about an overview of storage but also some new capabilities that were announcing
so, thank you very much for watching hopefully this...been very informative for you?